#### **ALLAN NIELSEN**

11028 Fernald Avenue Dallas, Texas 75218 214.843.0032 (Cell) allan.nielsen@gmx.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Services project leader and technical sales support professional with 12 years' experience in the telecommunications, IT service delivery/outsourcing, and software industries. Solid experience and well-rounded skills in customer facing service management, escalation management and incident/problem management environments. Calm, focused and with a professional demeanor, capable of defusing tense situations during critical issue escalation and stressful periods. Accomplished project manager that drives teams to develop, implement and operate technical solutions that meet customer needs. Well versed in continuous process and productivity improvements methodology. Fluent in German and Danish, with conversational French.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## TEKTRONIX COMMUNICATONS, Dallas, TX

2010-2011

Provider of real-time service assurance and customer experience solutions for advanced telecommunications networks, serving customers such as AT&T, Cricket and Telus.

## Client Services Program Manager, Americas

Program manager, escalation manager, and in-house customer advocate with responsibility for multiple North American accounts generating in excess of \$4M annual service revenue.

- Implemented proactive monitoring processes and actions, subsequently increasing critical system performance and usability KPIs to >90% on key customer systems.
- Supported sales organization in successfully achieving 100% maintenance agreement renewal rate of all managed Tier 1 accounts.
- Maintained customer satisfaction levels through account leadership, focus and dynamic resource allocation during internal organization changes with >70% attrition of experienced resources and on-boarding of new comers.
- Rapidly established strong relationships with key customer counterparts as well as internal sales, engineering and product line departments, facilitating the flow of customer requests from idea through implementation and to revenue recognition.

## THINPRINT, Berlin, Germany

2008-2009

Software focused firm offering a hi-tech print solution portfolio for server based computing environments including Citrix, VMware, and Windows Remote. Annual sales - \$13M.

#### Sales Director, Nordics

Regional sales representative responsible for sales in all Scandinavia plus Iceland and Faroe Islands.

- Rapidly acquired thorough understanding of a new technology, new market, and a new function within 2 months.
- Grew partner network by 25% including re-engaging a major Danish distributor.
- Nurtured partner independence via on-going technical training, sales strategy support and RFP response assistance
- Increased lead generation by 200% through personal presentations at partner sales

IBM (FORMERLY MÆRSK DATA), Copenhagen, Denmark

2003-2007

Global Services business unit delivering IT-outsourcing to large scale customers.

#### Situation Manager (2005–2007)

Major and critical incident manager and single point of contact, including disaster recovery, for AP Møller/Mærsk. Responsibilities included global operations of entire portfolio of IT systems (mainframe, windows, unix, oracle, sql, db2, middle-ware, websphere mq, EDI, and other company specific applications). Maersk revenues exceeded \$50BN annually.

- Selected as part of first time Situation Management team, reporting directly to C-level management, vested with global resolution of major and critical incidents.
- Maintained availability metrics (high-availability, ultrahigh-availability, and fault-tolerant systems) of AP Møller/Mærsk systems during 80% employee growth (from approximately 65,000 to 110.000) caused by the acquisition of P&O Nedlloyd.
- Resolved multiple incidents in critical systems, such as the MLIS booking system, where 60 minutes downtime equated to \$0.5M+ in lost revenues.
- Introduced feasibility study of revised fail-over environment for improvement of disaster recovery staff readiness.

## IT Specialist (2003 – 2004)

Customer support desk representative in charge of incident management and user administration for 65,000 global users within the AP Møller/Mærsk IT systems and network.

- Streamlined, restructured, and optimized indexation of some 2500 documents of the Service Desk knowledge database, as part of ITIL CMDB compliance.
- Improved the effectiveness of the experienced Service Desk agents and reduced the amount of time needed for training newly hired agents by approximately 30%.

# **NOKIA NETWORKS,** Copenhagen, Denmark Global telecommunications company.

1999-2002

## 2<sup>nd</sup> Level Support Engineer

Network implementation and customer operations technical support engineer for installed base of wire-line and wire-less telephony network equipment with national and international telecommunications operators.

- Part of an international team of engineers deployed to Greece to troubleshoot and repair a problematic MSC/HLR installation.
- Engaged in on-site consultancy to establish the first successful Virtual Network Operator in Danish wireline market.

## **EDUCATION**

BSc, University College of Copenhagen, Denmark Foundation in IT & Telecommunication Networks, overlay in Business Administration

HD part I Business Diploma, Copenhagen Business School, Denmark

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

PMP Certified, PMI
Account Management, Antares Consulting
ITIL Foundation Plus, IBM
IMAP, Maersk Data/IBM
Certified JAVA Programmer, CSC
Negotiation Skills, Nokia
2G – 3G GSM Technology, Nokia